hello everyone
today we are going to start our journey on TerraFirmGreg
as the name suggests
this is a modpack focused around Terrafirma and gregtech
but it also has a lot of create in it
as a Terraform pack
the world generation is completely customized
and there are a lot of things we should worry about
the first one is food
while it is easy to find it also has an expiration date
also we can't keep eating the same thing
we have to keep our diet balanced
to avoid running into issues
and we must also remember to drink some fluids if we do not want to pass out due to dehydration
finally
one other thing we have to keep track of is temperature and seasons
and since we spawned in a rather cold climate
we shall start our journey by migrating towards a more warm climate
so we start heading towards South
and while we do so
we shall also get prepared for the night
there won't be any weird creatures
but it will be quite dark
so we gather some sticks and polish them into a kit to start fires
then we make sure it works
but a random wildfire won't be much useful
so we start working on some tools to help us
we nap some of the rocks we gathered earlier on onto an axe head
which we attach to a broom
now that we have an axe
we can chop down the tree to gather some proper lumber
but doing so on a huge tree is going to take a lot of time
so we instead look around for an already fallen and dry tree
and this old tree is now so rotten
that it basically chops down itself on its own
with that lumber
we can now try to start a proper controlled fire
we must also add a couple of twigs
to help the fire catch on
and even then
we still have to try a couple of times to get the fire up
now that we have a proper managed fire
we can use it to slowly ignite the tip of some sticks
making torches
and with those
we can now keep going on our journey even during the darkest nights
and after a couple of days of walking
we found ourselves stuck on an island surrounded only by the ocean
and while we managed to find a better climate
this place isn't too good for setting up our settlement
so we are going to walk back a little bit
where the climate isn't too harsh
but the flora is great
now that we have found a nice place for our settlement
we have to find a nice place for all of the junk in our inventory
to do so
we start by gathering some clay by a Riverside
and in this pack
clay doesn't simply fall like sand
it even falls sideways when you move stuff close to it
anyways to speed up our gathering process
we are going to nap some stones
to make a rudimentary shovel
once we have enough
we can spend the night molding the clay into all kinds of shapes
and as you can probably tell
the thing we need the most right now is a vessel to store some items
but a clay vessel is too soft to be used
to harden it into ceramic
we put it in a hole in the ground
cover it with straw, some logs
and fire it up
the process will take 8 minutes
and we probably shouldn't have started it close to burnable stuff
the rain can't put off the pottery process
but it may helps us without mistake
maybe
and while we wait for our pottery to be done
we can prepare some more for the next task
moulding metal
thus we prepare clay moulds for the main tools we will want to be made out of bronze
and once again
we bury those in a hole in the ground under burnable stuff
then we pitch everything on fire
and we start making even more molds
and while those are ceramifying
we can start scouting around our base for metal rich pebbles
we mainly look for tin and copper rich stones
after collecting some
we go back home
where our first vessel is now ready
and can finally help us free up some of our inventory
and one nice feature is that
if we close the lid
it will double the food preservation time
next we take out of the Kiln our smaller vessels
those can be used as small backpacks
but the main use is melting metals
we could just melt some tetrahedrite to get some copper
but we want bronze
to get it
we have to melt it with some cassiterite
the ratio is not strict
so we can just go with something in the working range
and we can see if it works and how much we get just by hovering over the vessel after filling it with rocks
once satisfied
we fire it up to melt the metals
then as soon as the fires goes out
we retrieve it while it's still hot enough for the metal to be molten
and the first thing we want to use it for is a saw
we also manage to make a prospector pickaxe
and a normal pickaxe
once the metal cooled down
we take it out of its molds
and use it to craft an usable tool
then we use our new saw to cut some lumber out of the logs we have
which we work into a crafting table and a proper chest
and now that I look at those
I think we couldn't have picked a worse looking wood
so we recraft everything with a better looking one
but to continue our adventure
we will need more metal
and the pebbles on the surface do not suffice
to find bigger deposits of metal
we use prospector pick by metal rich pebbles to locate surface ore deposits
once we locate some
we start digging towards it
but this is Terra firma
so even digging a tunnel is not as easy as you'd hope
if we are not careful
even solid rock can fall on us
to prevent that
we need support beams
each one will safeguard the nearby rocks from falling
and we have to build one every fixed amount of blocks
now we can just keep looking around
until we find the ores we are looking for
and we get a better yield by breaking those with a hammer
and during our mining operation
we found one more hazard we weren't ready for
some minerals are toxic and will poison us
and it looks like the poison was strong enough that
even after getting rid of the hazardous material
we still pass out
this lead us to an even more annoying issue
we respawned almost 4000 blocks away
and having to walk all the way to our settlement every time this happens is not a good thing
so after walking all the way back to the mine
making a backup
isolating the toxic stuff
and retrieving our stuff
we start working on a bed
this will need some soft material
and the easiest way is to just roughly mold a sword
to collect some sheepskin from some alpackers
we can separate the wool from the leather with a knife
but it's still too rough to be used
so we use a spindle to make it into yarns
then with the help of a loom
we make some cloth
which we can finally use for our bed
now we will respawn at our base
the next issue we should worry about is
stocking up some food for the winter
the main issue is that most food expires quickly
but we can work around that by for example cooking it
and now that we have meet our basic needs
we shall work on meeting the basic needs of our upcoming factory
thus we start gathering a lot of copper rich stones
and to melt it we will need a lot of wood
and here chopping down a whole tree into logs, sticks and saplings takes probably more time than doing it IRL
luckily for whatever reason
we can speed up the process by crouching
thus leaving aside the small branches
however while the lumber we obtained is good enough for a pottery Kiln
it's not optimal for proper metal working
so we make a charcoal pit to turn it into better stuff
to do so, we simply bury some log piles
and then pitch those on fire
we must be very careful
the wood must not be in contact with air
or it will only leave ash behind
and after a day or so
the process completed
turning the logs into charcoal
which we can now dig out
then we stick some in a hole surrounded by rocks
and pitch it on fire
making a rudimentary forge
we fill it with more charcoal, some molds
and then we throw in the raw minerals we want to melt
after enough time
the metal will flow out of the rocks
and fall into the molds
from which we can then extract ingots
to work with those ingots
we will need some hard material to smash those on
but the rocks we have here are too soft
we found a rock hard enough for the task in our cave
but bringing it back home is no easy task
if we use our pickaxe
the rocks breaks into pebbles
same things happens with a hammer
the way we can actually extract a whole cube of rock
is by breaking all of the connected blocks that touch it
leaving it almost floating into air
at which point it falls as a single piece
we bring that piece of Hard Rock next to our forge
and turn it into a primitive anvil
the first thing we will want to do with it
is meld together two copper ingots
but of course
no matter how much we smash those together
we first have to heat them up
so we fire up our forge
and wait for the ingots to become hot enough to glow orange
then before they melt or cool down
we take those to the anvil
but moving glowing hot ingots with our bare hands wasn't our brightest idea
to help us with the task
we get a couple of sticks
but in the meantime
the ingots cooled down too much
so we heat up those again
and we better have some molds to safeguard eventual molten metal spills
once we reach temperature
we try again to weld those
and this time
we realize we also need some fluxing material
luckily
the soft stone we have here is a sedimentary rock
which can be smashed into flux
and with that we can finally get a double ingot
don't mind the missing texture
with enough of those
we can make a slightly better anvil
this one not only looks better
but it will also allow us to work harder materials
such as bronze
long story short
we now have a bronze anvil
but a proper anvil is made at least of iron
but at the moment
we do not have the tools to melt the iron out of rocks
instead we have to work it in a bloomery
and that machine requires quite a lot of bronze
and that means a lot of copper
to save on copper
we can use a different kind of bronze
which can be made with less copper
and instead uses some less useful and more abundant minerals
bismuth bronze
and we can also increase the yield of our copper ores
by first cleaning some of the impurities in a river
and then smashing it into a finer powder
to ease the extraction of molten metal
finally we wash off the soluble dust
and we are left with pure mineral dust
which will yield almost twice as much metal
allowing us to overflow a vessel
thus turning all of our precious minerals into trash
and now we have to gather more and start over
paying attention not to overflow the vessel
for the next task
having a double ingot won't be enough
we have to hammer it into a proper plate
and it must be done properly
this means we have to keep hitting the thing
until it's flat enough
but without any hole
after enough hammering
we managed to get our first plate
but that was too thin
so we made a second one
heated both of those up
and hammered them into a thicker one
14 plates later
we managed to make a bloomery
but to use that
we also need some bricks
so we dissolve some lime in water
add some sand
and let it in for a couple of hours to get mortar
next we take some of the pebbles we made while gathering ores
and chisel those into bricks
which we then turn into blocks
we used those to build a chimney for our broomery
and since those bricks are cheap and nice looking
we also used them to made the walls of our future house
next we throw some iron rich minerals with some charcoal in our broomery
and pitch it on fire
this process will take a long time
and it will leave us with some iron blooms
we dig those out using a pickaxe
then with the help of an anvil
we hammer those into wrought iron ingots
which we use to upgrade our anvil
the next tier is steel
but to get it we have a longer road ahead
we will need a couple of new machinery
but it all starts from a basic material we don't even have
pink clay
the main issue is that
this material can only be found in the humid and hot tropical biomes
which are far from us
and it looks like we have to find a way around the ocean if we want to get there
the best way to achieve so is probably to get a boat
and we have many choices
but not all of them are available
some are expensive and require steel
anyways
the first step for making a good enough boat is some scaffolding
to hold it in place while we build it
next we need the planks
that will actually constitute the structure
and to stick everything together
we can use some copper bolts
which we can make by first hammering an ingot into a rod
and then cutting it with a saw
and while working on the anvils
we also smite a couple of oar locks
finally we get a couple of ore
so that we can start assembling the thing
we start by building a structure with the scaffolds
then we fill it up using the planks
next with the help of a hammer
we insert the copper bolts into the structure
to keep everything in place
and to complete our new boat
we add the oar locks
to use it we add the oars and jump on it
this ship is powered by the magical oars
that work whenever you stare at them
and before we take off to the sea
with our hunger for adventures
we add some chests for extra inventory for our loot
we should have probably took some food
some water and a backpack
but I think a backup will suffice
and after a really long adventure across the ocean
we finally found land
but after the first phase of happiness
the long chain of despair came
this was just an island
next to it another volcanic island
and Big Sandy shore island
with nothing interesting on them
luckily not too far we found again land
this time a continent made of hills
we found many new plants there
but not luck with the clay we were looking for
so we started circum navigating it
but to avoid a swamp
we moved inside the continent in a river to check it out
and it was then that we spotted a suspicious red flower
upon closer inspection
it actually was the blood Lily
which only spawns above the clay we are looking for
however after digging we didn't find anything
and the flower now lost it petals
and looks like normal grass
but after a few more steps
we finally found the pink clay
just below another flower which decided to unbloom to make the search harder for us
we fill our inventory and our ship with all of that pink gold
then we head back home
and when we park our ship
we notice the wind was pushing it to the open sea
since we do not have the steel for a pole to keep it leashed
we enclose it in our new pool
now that we have the clay
we have to dry it into powder
to heat it up
we fire up our forge
however after not much
we realize this process is rather slow and tedious
to make it easier to manage
instead of heating single pieces of clay
we fill up a vessel and heat that instead
after a long time and a lot of charcoal it worked
but our vessel is now too hot to be opened
so we cool it down in a water bath
with that we now have our kaolinite clay powder
but that wasn't really enough
so repeat the process
and this time we use a Kiln pit instead of the forge
while we wait
we can work on the other ingredient required for the next step
graphite
and to locate it
we can follow our best buddy
Diamond buds
those indicate and underneath carbon vein
and we can already gather some tiny amounts of graphite on the surface
after some digging
we found a cave
which also exposed the mineral we were looking for
we collect some of it
and then we process it into pure dust
but it wasn't dusty enough
so we use our new quern to grind it down into a finer powder
we mix it with the other two kinds of clay
into fire clay
which we can mold into a crucible
and as with normal clay
we have to fire it up in the forge
to turn it into ceramic
but after a long wait
we figured out this wasn't going to work
we have to heat it up at yellow white 4
however our charcoal burns at yellow white 2
one solution could be using a better fuel
such as the coal we found in the diamond graphite vein
but we don't have much of it
so we keep it for better purposes
instead we work on the new tool
which start from taking the hide left over from processing wool
this one is too rough and dirty
so we start the cleaning process
by sinking it into lime water
then to get a sturdy table
we get a lumber and clean it from it bark
now we can lay the prepared hide on it
and start the scratching process
once we finish scratching the hide
we put it in a barrel with fresh water
to clean up all the residues
finally after preparing some tanning agent
we soak the cleaned hide in it to get proper leather
with this we can now craft our new tool
to boost the temperature of our forge
bellow
and it was then that we realized it's already winter
and we still don't have a roof
so after quickly using our new toy to complete the crucible
we also complete our roof
and this place not only is cold enough for icicles to form
it is also quite dark
and torches here burn out after two days
we can nap a pumpkin to obtain a decoration
that will double the duration
but it's still not much
another cool option is to make lamps
but those are cool to make only the first time
the first step is to get the metal frame
which we can do in the anvil
and then we need the glass
we prepare the base compound
by mixing a couple of easy to gather materials
then we apply that over a ceramic blowpipe and heat it up
once we get it in our hands
it's too hot so we instinctively throw it away
after getting a second blowpipe
to prevent burns from the first one
we start trying to figure out how to manage all the tools we have to use to do our glasswork
as usual
we can find a better explanation in the TerraFirm guide book
so with the help of a blowpipe in one hand
we take the hot blowpipe with the other hand
we swap tools
and then we blow in the pipe with the hot glass
then we pinch it
and before it gets too cold to the point it can no longer be worked
we put it back in the forge
once we get it back
we hit it with a paddle and then blow again
finally we heat it up one last time before we cut out the molded glass sphere for our lantern
we can combine it with the metal frame to get a lantern
but of course that still needs fuel
for that we can use creosote oil
which we can feed with pipes from our new coke oven
the only thing left to do is to light it up using an already lit torch
with that touch of light and technology
our shelter looks a new
but while this is nice and all
there are other issues we have to face
the lake nearby our house is icing
thus making water more of an issue
to help with that
we craft an iron flask
that will help us bring water wherever we go
and we fill it with the water leftover from working leather
now we can sip fresh clean water wherever we want
but other than water
we also need some better food
we can get some by grinding into finer powder some of our wheat leftovers
then we take some water and make a dough with that flour
we make some bread loaves
and cook those with the help of grill to better control the cooking
finally we add some veggies and meat
to make some nice sandwiches
but one other food we can make more ideal for this climate is soup
we put a pot on the fire and fill it with water
then we add some ingredients and make it boil
once it's done
we fill some bowls
and have a nice feast
the only thing we need now
is a better way to carry all of those new things
and to carry all of that weight
we shall use something made of a strong material
such as jute fibre
which we loom into burlap cloth
with that we can assemble a backpack
finally we can bring our anvils with us wherever we go
without getting slowed down
and this is going to be our new best friend
when we will be gathering more iron for the upcoming episode
see you next time
bye bye
大家好
今天我们要开始TerrafirmaGreg旅程了
正如这个整合包名
这是一个围绕群峦传说和给格雷科技的整合包
但同时也有很多机械动力内容
作为一个群峦包
世界生成被大改了
而且还有更多事要担心
首先是食物
尽管食物遍地都是
但它们都有保质期
而且我们不能只吃一种食物
我们必须保证营养均衡
来避免引发问题
而且为了避免因为脱水而晕过去
我们必须记得补充液体
最后
我们也要关注温度和季节
既然我们出生在了一个很冷的地方
我们应该启程去到一个更温暖的地带
所以我们开始向南进发
与此同时
我们应该开始准备过夜
tfc的夜晚不会有什么危险生物
但仍然会很黑
所以我们捡几根树枝
做了一把钻木取火的工具
随后我们确保这东西可用
但这样随手点的火没什么用
所以我们开始做一些有用的工具
我们把先前收集的石头打制成斧头
并把它绑在一个斧柄上
现在我们有了把斧头
可以砍树来收集点木材
但砍这些大树很耗时
所以我们转而寻找一些已经倒下的树
这些干枯朽木腐朽到了
会自己倒下
有了这些木材
我们可以做一个可控的篝火
除此之外还需要加两个树枝
来辅助点火
尽管如此
我们仍然要花时间尝试几次才能点起火
现在我们有了篝火
可以用来缓慢地点燃一些木棍
来做火把
有了这些
我们现在可以昼夜兼行了
几天几夜的徒步后
我们发现自己被困在了被海洋环绕的一个大岛上
尽管我们找到了还不错的气候区
但那地方并不适合定居
所以我们决定往回走一点
到一个气候不算恶劣
但植被很丰富的地区
现在我们找到了一片建家的好地方
也得给我们背包里的这堆破烂找个家
为此
我们在河边收集一些黏土
在这个整合包里
黏土不仅会像沙子一样有重力
在你挖掉它旁边的方块时它还会向侧边滑落
总之为了加快收集黏土的速度
我们又打了一些石头
来做铲子
一旦我们收集了足够多
我们就花一整晚来将它们捏成各种形状
你可能看出来了
要存下这些物品，我们最需要的是大缸
但是刚捏出来的黏土缸还太软
为了将它烧成能用的陶罐
我们把它放进坑里
覆盖上干草和木材
并将其点燃
烧制需要8分钟
而且我们最好保证旁边没有可燃物
下雨不会影响烧陶器的进度
但雨也许能帮我们灭一灭火
也许吧
等待它完成的时候
我们可以为下个任务做更多准备
也就是冶金
因此我们为青铜工具制作了铸模
再一次地
我们挖了坑，并用燃料把铸模埋进坑里
随后点火
我们又制作了更多模具
等待烧制的时间里
我们可以在家周围逛逛
找一些地表的矿粒
现在我们主要找锡和铜
收集了一些矿粒之后
我们回家
我们的第一个大缸已经准备好了
终于可以用它来释放一些背包空间
大缸还有一个很好的特性
关上缸盖后
其中的食物保质期会延长一倍
接着我们拿出小缸
它们可以当成小背包用
但它的主要功能是熔化金属
我们可以熔化一些黝铜矿来获得铜
但我们想要的是青铜
要获得青铜
我们需要在冶炼时加入一些锡石
合金的比例不是特别严格
将它保持在那个区间里就可以
我们只需要将指针悬停在物品上
看tooltip里的生成物提示就好了
一但我们觉得满意
我们就点燃坑窑来熔炼它们
等火一灭
我们在它还热得让金属保持液态的时候就立刻拿起小缸
我们用它做的第一个东西是锯片
我们又设法做了探矿镐
和一把普通镐子
一旦金属冷却
我们就将其脱模
并用来合成一些可使用的工具
我们用新锯子从原木中切出木材
好用来做工作台和箱子
做完我们才发现
我们选的木头太难看了
所以我们将它们全部换成了更好看的材质
但接下来的冒险中
我们还需要更多金属
而地表的金属粒完全不够用‘
为了找到更大的矿脉
我们在金属粒周围使用勘矿镐
来确定地表的矿物分布
一旦我们定位到一些矿石
我们就向下挖掘
但这里是群峦
就算挖洞也比想象中难
如果我们不够小心
就连硬质岩石也会砸在我们身上
为了防止坍塌
我们需要支撑梁
每一根支撑梁都会防止周围的方块坠落
我们每隔一段距离就放一些
现在我们可以在矿道里寻找
直到找到我们需要的矿物
用锤子采矿可以增产
在采矿的过程中
我们遇到了未预料的危险
一些矿物是有毒的，会毒害我们
且似乎这种毒性强到
即便我们丢掉这些有毒矿物
我们仍然被毒死了
这给我们带来了一个更烦人的问题
我们重生在了4000格外的位置
每次我们死亡后都要跑这么远不是一件好事
所以在长途跋涉回到矿道后
我们存了一个备份
挑出有毒矿物
并捡回了我们的尸体
我们开始准备做床
这需要一些柔软的材料
最简单的方法就是随便做一把剑
然后去找羊驼们借一点羊皮
用小刀把羊毛从羊皮上弄下来
但这样的羊毛还是粗制的不能直接用
所以我们用纺锤将其纺成羊毛纱
随后在织布机的帮助下
我们获得了一些羊毛布
可以用来做床
现在我们就可以重生在家里了
我们要关心的第二件事是
为过冬而准备的食物
问题在于大多数食物过期得很快
但我们有办法解决，比如将它烤熟
而现在我们已经满足了生存的基本需求
是时候着手于即将到来的工业化了
于是我们开始收集大量的铜矿石
将其熔炼，我们还需要很多木头
然而在这里砍树花的时间
大概比现实里砍倒一棵树还要久
不过幸运的是，不知出于什么原因
蹲下的同时砍树会获得加速
同时还不会产生副产的木棍
我们费劲获得的木材烧陶器还不错
但并不适合金属加工
所以我们做了一个木炭坑来制炭
只需要在坑里埋一些原木
然后点火
我们必须小心
不能让燃烧的木头和空气接触
否则它们会烧成灰烬
过一天左右
烧制完成了
木头被烧成了木炭
我们现在可以把它们挖下来
随后我们把木炭摆进由石头环绕的坑里
点上火
获得了一个基础的木炭炉
我们添加一些木炭和铸模
再放入我们想熔炼的矿石
足够长时间后
熔融金属会流出矿石
再流进铸模里
之后我们就可以从中取出金属锭
要加工这些金属锭
我们需要一些足够硬的材料来将锭放在上面锤锻
但这里的石头都太软了
我们在矿洞里找到了足够硬的石头
但把它们带回家不是件容易的事情
如果我们用镐子挖掉
它会碎成石子
就算用锤子也一样
要完整取得一块石头
我们需要破坏与目标相连的所有方块
使之几乎悬空
随后它会以一整个方块掉落
我们把这块坚硬的石头带回到木炭炉旁边
用锤子将其变成石砧
我们要用它做的第一件事
是焊接一个铜双锭
不过当然
不管我们如何敲打
都得先把它们加热
所以我们点起木炭炉
等铜锭烧到橙温度
在它熔化或冷却之前
我们将其放在砧上
但空手转移红热的金属锭不是个好主意
为了完成任务
我们用一对木棍夹取它们
但与此同时
它们已经冷却了
所以我们重新加热它们
我们最好放几个铸模做保险
以防金属熔化消失掉
一旦到达可焊接温度
我们再试一次焊接
而这一次
我们意识到还需要一些助焊剂
幸运的是
我们周围的石头是沉积岩
它们可以被打碎成助焊剂
有了这些，我们终于获得了双锭
不要在意这个贴图丢失
有足够多的双锭后
我们可以做出更好一点的砧
铜砧不只更好看
我们还可以用它处理更硬的金属
比如青铜
总之
我们现在有了青铜砧
但一个合格的砧起码得是铁做的
但暂时
我们没有能够从矿石中熔炼铁的工具
相反，我们需要用锻铁炉进行加工
而锻铁炉又需要相当多的青铜
也意味着相当多的铜
为了节约铜
我们可以换一种青铜
它需求更少的铜
取而代之的是一些不那么有用但储量更丰富的矿物
也就是铋青铜
我们还可以对铜矿进行增产
首先用水洗去杂质
然后把它敲成更细的粉末
使得熔炼更加容易
随后我们洗掉其中的可溶部分
只剩下纯净的矿粉
相比之下可以几乎增产一倍
这也使得产物溢出了小缸
让我们的珍贵矿石变成了垃圾
现在我们只能再多收集一些
且注意不要让产量溢出容器
为了下一个任务
仅有双锭还不够
我们必须将其锤锻成合格的板材
而锤锻的过程必须适当
这意味着我们必须不停敲击
使其足够平整
且没有孔洞
经历了足够的锤锻后
我们获得了第一块板
但它太单薄了
所以我们锻造了第二块
将二者加热
并焊接在一起
再做出14块板后
我们最终做出了锻铁炉
但是，要使用它
我们还需要一些砖块
我们将一些石灰溶入水中
加入一些沙子
并封存几个小时来获得砂浆
接下来我们拿一些挖矿时收集的石子
用凿子将其凿成砖块
最后制成石砖方块
我们用这些石砖建造了锻铁炉的烟囱
且这些砖块便宜又好看
我们也将用它们来做我们未来的家的墙壁
我们往锻铁炉里丟一些铁矿石和木炭
并点着火
冶炼需要花费很长时间
它会留下生铁方坯
我们用镐将它们挖出来
接下来借助青铜砧
我们将它们锤锻成锻铁锭
随后用这些锻铁升级了砧
下一阶段是钢
但要获得它，我们还有很长的路要走
我们需要一些新设备
但这些都要从一种我们尚未获得的材料开始
高岭土
最大的问题是
高岭土只能在潮湿又炎热的群系中找到
离我们很远
要到达那的话，我们必须想办法跨越这片海洋
最好的办法是做一艘船
并且在船的种类上我们还有不少选择
但目前并不所有的都可选
有些船造价很贵且需要钢
总之
做一艘足够好的船的第一步是做一些船架
好让我们在搭建时固定船体
接下来是一些木板
用来构成船体结构
为了钉住所有方块
我们可以做一些铜螺栓
我们先将锭锤锻成杆
随后用锯子将其切断
与此同时
我们还做了一对桨座
最后再做一对船桨
我们就可以开始组装船了
第一步用脚手架搭出结构
再用木板填充
接下来借助锤子的力量
我们将铜螺栓钉进船体结构
好保证船不散架
为了完成我们的新船
我们为之加上桨座
装上船桨，跳上去来使用这艘船
这艘船的动力源是魔法船桨
只要你盯着它们看，它们就会转起来
在我们怀着探险的渴望
出海之前
我们加装了一些箱子来作为储存战利品的额外空间
我们还应该够带些食物
以及水和背包
不过我觉得保存一个备份就足够了
在跨海的长途跋涉后
我们终于发现了新大陆
但最初的喜悦过后
接踵而至的是更多的失望
我们发现的只是座岛
紧挨着的是一个火山岛
和另一个只有沙滩的大岛
同样什么都没有
但幸运的是
在不远的地方我们再次发现了陆地
这次是一块由丘陵构成的大陆
在这里我们找到了许多新植被
但不幸的是并没有高岭土
所以我们开始绕海岸线航行
然而为了避开一片沼泽
我们驶入一条从内陆流出来的河流来一探究竟
就在那时我们发现了一种可疑的红色花
仔细观察后
我们发现这是火球花
而这种花只会长在高岭土之上
然而挖掘后我们却什么都没找到
而且那花此时也失去了花瓣
看起来和普通的草没什么两样
但就在周围
我们终于找到了高岭土
就在那个决定谢掉花瓣来增添我们寻找难度的那朵花旁边
我们用这些高岭土填满了背包
随后回家
停好船后
我们意识到风在把我们的船推向大海
而我们还没有钢来制作柱子拴住船
只好把它围在小水泊里
既然有了高岭土
我们就把它们烘干烤成粉末
为了加热它们
我们点燃了木炭炉
然而没过多久
我们就意识到这样处理又慢又无聊
为了简化流程
我们不再一个一个烧
取而代之的是用小缸装满后一起加热
经过很长时间，耗费了很多木炭后，它终于完成了
但此时还太热，不能打开
所以我们在水坑里冷却它
现在我们有了高岭石粉
但这些实际上还不够
所以我们重复这个过程
这次我们换用坑窑代替木炭炉
等待的时候
我们可以着手于下一个任务所需的材料
石墨
要找到它
我们可以先找到我们最好的朋友
钻石芽
它们指示着底下的含碳矿脉
并且我们已经可以在地表收集少量的石墨粉了
向下挖掘一会后
我们发现了一个矿洞
其中有着裸露的石墨矿
我们挖了一些原矿
将它们处理成纯净粉末
但它还粉碎得不够细
所以我们用新的手推磨将其磨得更细
再将其与高岭石粉和黏土混合
得到了耐火黏土
我们可以将其捏成坩埚
和普通黏土一样
我们必须将它在放在木炭炉里烧制
来制成陶器
但经过很长时间后
我们意识到这样行不通
我们必须将其加热到黄白****(4)才行
然而我们的木炭最多只能烧到黄白**(2)
一种解决方案是使用更好的燃料
比如我们在钻石石墨矿脉里收集到的煤炭
但我们的存量很少
所以我们把它留下以备更好的用途
取而代之的是，我们制作一种新工具
从处理获取羊毛而留下的兽皮开始
这些兽皮还太粗糙太脏
所以我们开始清洁
首先将其浸泡在石灰水中
接下来为了获得一张足够结实的桌子
我们放下一块原木并剥掉树皮
现在我们可以把准备好的兽皮铺在上面
开始进行刮制
一旦我们完成了刮制皮革
我们将其封存在装有淡水的大桶里
清理掉所有残留
最后再准备一些鞣酸
将预制皮革在其中浸泡来得到真正的皮革
有了它，我们现在就可以合成我们的新工具
来提高木炭炉温度
也就是风箱
而这时我们才意识到已经入了冬季
而我们的家还没有屋顶
所以在用我们的新玩具来做出坩埚后
我们很快也做好了屋顶
这地方不仅冷到会产生冰溜子
还很黑
然而火把在tfc里只能烧两天
我们可以塑形一个南瓜来做装饰
它还会让火把的燃烧时间加倍
但这仍然不够
另一个不错的选择是灯
但大概只有第一次做的时候会觉得有趣
第一步是在砧上制作灯的金属框架
随后我们需要玻璃
我们准备了一种
由几种很容易获得的材料混合而成的混合物
将混合物置于陶瓷吹风管上，再加热它
但刚拿出来时它还太热
我们本能地将其丢掉了
在使用第二根吹风管
来避免我们被前一根烫伤后
我们开始琢磨如何操作我们的这些工具来完成玻璃
照例
我们可以在群峦手册里找到说明
所以我们在一只手上拿吹风管
另一只手拿上带有熔融玻璃的热吹风管
交换主副手
向吹风管内吹气
接下来挤压它
在玻璃冷到无法继续处理之前
我们将其放回木炭炉重新加热
一旦将其取出
我们用压板挤压它，随后再次吹气
最后，在我们切下处理完成的灯罩前
我们最后一次地加热它
将灯罩和框架组合在一起后
我们最终获得了灯
不过它仍然需要燃料
为此我们可以用杂酚油
通过管道从我们的新焦炉来供给它
最后一件事就是
用已经点燃了的火把点燃灯
有了这么一丝光明和初步的科技发展
我们的火柴盒看起来焕然一新
虽然现在一切都好起来了
我们仍然需要面对不少问题
我们家旁边的湖正在封冻
这使得水成为了一个问题
为了解决它
我们做了一个铁水壶
这可以让我们把水带在身上
我们用之前处理皮革剩下的水来填满水壶
现在我们可以随时随地喝上干净的水了
但除此之外
我们还需要更好的食物
我们先把一些剩下的小麦磨成更细的粉末
随后我们加入水来做成面团
在能更好地控制的烤架的帮助下
我们做出了几条面包
最后我们加入一些蔬菜和肉
来做出一些美味的三明治
除此之外更加适合这个寒冷气候的食物是汤
我们将陶锅架在火上并加入水
接着加入食材后将其煮沸
一旦完成
我们用一些碗来盛汤
饱餐了一顿
现在我们唯一缺少的
是一个能装下这些新东西的更好办法
为了能承担这些重量
我们需要一些由坚固材料制成的东西
比如黄麻纤维
我们可以将它制成粗麻布
有了它，我们现在可以做一个背包
而现在我们就可以随身带着砧
同时也不会拖慢我们的速度
这个背包也将成为
我们收集更多铁矿时的好朋友
不过那是下一集的故事了
下次见
拜拜